（洛杉磯公元2029年）
（那些機器從核子戰火中崛起）
（它們滅絕人類的戰肆虐數十年）
（但最後的一場仗不會在未來掀起）
（它會發生在這裡，就是現在）
（就在今晚）
片名：魔鬼終結者
（洛杉磯 1984年早上1點52分）
怎麼了？ 他媽的…
What the hell...? Goddamn son-of-a-bitch...
怎麼回事？
What the hell...?
- 哇 - 輪到我了
Hey, my turn.
來吧
這個人搞什麼鬼？
Hey, what's wrong with this picture?
夜色很好，適宜散步
Nice night for a walk?
Nice night for a walk.
明天是洗衣日，沒乾淨衣服穿
Wash day tomorrow. Nothing clean,
是嗎？
right?
對，沒乾淨衣服
Nothing clean. Right.
這個傢伙一定是喝醉了
I think this guy's a couple of cans short of a six-pack.
你的衣服. 馬上給我.
Your clothes, give them to me. Now.
去你的，混蛋
Fuck you, asshole.
嘿，甜心，怎麼樣？
我不必忍受那個的
她老是纏著我
兄弟，你有沒有見到一道強光？
Hey, buddy, did you just see a real bright light?
看到那傢伙嗎？
See that guy?
別動
Hold it right there.
- 他在逃跑 - 別動
- He's rabbiting. - Hey! I said hold it!
去吧
Go!
那個混蛋…搶了我的褲子
That son-of-a-bitch took my pants.
今天是什麼日子？日期
What day is it? The date.
5月12號
12th May.
- 星期四 - 什麼年份？
- Thursday. - What year?
什麼？
他搶了我的槍，快追
He's got my gun. Let's go.
（莎拉康納）
大塊頭，替我守著它
Guard it for me, Big Buns.
你好，我遲到了
Hi. I'm late.
我也是
Soam .
（莎拉康納）
- 開工了 - 我也是
-I'minit. -Soaml.
- 麻煩你拿咖啡給我，好嗎？ - 好的
- Honey, can I have that coffee now? - Yes, sir.
- 牛排是誰的？ - 我叫了烤牛肉
- OK. Who gets the burly-beef? - I ordered barbecued.
- 我沒有薯條 - 他要牛肉
I think that's mine, but I didn't order fries.
我叫的是辣牛肉
Mine's the chili beef deluxe.
誰點牛排？
OK, who gets the burly-beef?
- 小姐？我們想點菜 - 好的
- Miss, we're ready to order now. - Yes, ma'am.
天啊
對不起
I'm so sorry.
這不是真皮吧？
This isn't real leather, is it?
孩子，做得好，我該把小費給你
Nice going, kid. I ought to give you the tip.
要這樣想，一百年後誰會在乎？
Look at it this way. In 100 years, who's gonna care?
（阿萊姆體育用品槍械店）
那支12口徑自動步槍
The 12-gauge auto-loader.
義大利製造
That's Italian.
可以選手動或自動
You can go pump or auto.
點45口徑滑動式配雷射瞄準器
The .45 long slide with laser sighting.
它們是全新的，才剛收到 是支好槍
These are new. We just got them in. That's a good gun.
雷射光亮起時
Just touch the trigger, the beam comes on,
你把紅點對準目標就行
and you put the red dot where you want the bullet to go.
百發百中
You can't miss.
還有什麼需要？
Anything else?
一支40瓦的同步等離子步槍
Plasma rifle in the 40-watt range.
就是你看到的了
Hey, just what you see, pal.
那支烏茲型九毫米
The Uzi nine millimeter.
你很熟識槍械
You know your weapons, buddy.
任何一支都適合家居防衛
Any one of these is ideal for home defense.
那麼…要哪一支呢？
So which will it be?
-全部  -今天可以提早關門了
- All. - I may close early today.
手槍要等15天
It's a 15-day wait on the handguns,
但你現在可拿走那些步槍
but the rifles you can take now.
你不能這樣做
You can't do that.
錯
Wrong.
你好，寶貝
Hi, baby. Yeah, yeah,
是我
it's me.
我要你來接我，我的摩托車壞了
Listen, I need you to come pick me up. My bike just broke down.
我不管，來接我，什麼…
I don't care what you're doing. Come and get me. What the...?
莫特？
你的態度很有問題
Hey, man, you got a serious attitude problem.
莫特，你在哪裡？
別這樣，你在幹什麼？
（莎拉康納…）
- 莎拉康納？  - 是的
- Sarah Connor? -Yes?
我在休息，卡拉代替我
I'm on my break, Chuck. Carla's got my station.
莎拉，過來，這算是跟你有關的
Sarah, come here. It's about you. I mean, sort of.
不可思議，你不會相信的
So incredible. You're not gonna believe this.
坐下，你會喜歡這個的
Sit, you're going to love this.
- 什麼？  -...有幾個目擊證人指出
- What? - ...compiled from several witnesses.
一位莎拉康納 35歲，有兩名子女
Once again, Sarah Connor, 35, mother of two,
今天下午在家裡中槍身亡
brutally shot to death in her home this afternoon.
你死了
You're dead, honey.
如果你喜歡音響，
...If you're into sound,
最佳的音響…
for the greatest sound around,
就是鮑博立體聲
come to Bob's Stereo at 2500 Sepulveda.
我們有低音喇叭、高頻喇叭...
We've got woofers, tweeters,
...數位揚聲器和鐳射唱片
the newest in audio and compact discs.
還有圖表等化器和音響平衡器…
We've got graphic equalizers and sound balancers that...
對不起
Sorry.
你好
Hello?
首先，我會一個個的解開你的鈕扣
First I'm gonna rip the buttons off your blouse one by one,
然後用我的舌頭 從你的頭舔到你赤裸的乳房
then run my tongue down your neck...
...to your bare, gleaming breasts.
然後，慢慢地…
And then slowly...
逐吋地脫掉你的牛仔褲
slowly pull your jeans off inch by inch.
金珍，是麥特
Ginger, it's Matt.
然後打圈地舔你的肚皮…
And lick your belly in circles...
再往下面去
... further and further down,
然後用牙齒…
and then pull your panties off with my teeth.
脫掉你的內褲
你是誰？
Who is this?
天啊，莎拉？
God. Sarah?
我的天，對不起
Jesus. I'm sorry.
我以為你是…我想找金珍
I thought you were... Can I talk to Ginger, please?
好的，老友
Sure.
是那個變態鬼
It's the creep.
Hello?
首先，我會一個個解開你的鈕扣
First I'll rip the buttons off your blouse one by one...
冷靜點
你們這班混蛋.
You fucking pigs!
等著我對付你們，放手!
Wait till I get my hands on you. Get off me!
坐下
艾特
Ed.
- 你有什麼？ - 女性死者
- What have you got? - Dead girl.
我有看到
I can see that.
莎拉康納，秘書，35歲
Sarah Ann Connor, secretary, 35.
在不足十呎內身中六槍.
Shot six times at less than ten feet.
大口徑的武器
Large caliber weapon.
我看得清楚
You know, these work.
- 這是什麼？ - 第二名女性死者
- What's this? - Dead girl two.
今天下午山谷區分區送過來的
Sent over from the Valley division this afternoon.
我肯定這些命案是有動機的
Are you sure there's a point to all of this?
看看死者的名字
Look at the name, Ed.
莎拉…
Sarah Louise Connor. Is this right?
康…有沒有弄錯？
你說笑吧
You're kidding me.
報紙會大做文章的
The press is gonna be short-stroking it.
一個在一天內有特定模式的兇手
A one-day pattern killer.
我討厭古怪的案件
I hate the weird ones.
所以…
So...
比凡人得到的更好
Better than mortal man deserves.
- 你有沒有見過寶斯利？ - 最近沒有
- Ginger, have you seen Pugsley? - Not lately.
你聽了留言沒有？
Did you check messages?
我以為你聽了
I thought you did.
莎拉，是媽
Hi, Sarah, this is your mom...
原來你在這裡
There you are, young man.
你想想你媽吧
You mind your mother.
再見
你好，莎拉，史丹莫斯基.  有突發事件...
Hi, Sarah. Stan Morsky. Something's come up.
...令我不能應約了
Looks like I won't be able to make it tonight.
我不能丟下不理的
Just can't get out of it.
對不起，我會給你賠罪的
I'm really sorry. I'll make it up to you.
改天找你吧，對不起，再見
Call you in a day or so. Bye.
那個混蛋，有輛保時捷又怎樣
That bum. So what if he has a Porsche?
他不能這樣對待你的
He can't treat you like this.
這是週五晚上
It's Friday night, for Christ's sake.
我沒事的
I'll live.
我會打爆他的膝蓋
I'll break his kneecaps.
寶斯利仍然愛我，是嗎？
Well, Pugsley still loves me. Don't you, baby?
天，真噁心
God. It's disgusting.
我去看電影
I'm gonna go to a movie, kiddo.
你和麥特玩得開心點
Have a good time.
- 我們會的. 你也是. - 好的
- We will. You, too. - OK.
該死，麥特
Damn it, Matt.
該死
- Oh, shit. - Lieutenant!
你們可有察覺那些命案
These killings occurred in the order of...
是依電話簿裡的次序發生的？
...their listings in the phone book.
我可以說什麼？無可奉告
What can I tell you? No comment.
但是發生了兩宗命案…
But, Lieutenant...
那杯咖啡早就涼了
That coffee's two hours cold.
我還用它弄熄香煙
I put a cigarette out in it.
你能找到下一名女子嗎？
Did you reach the next girl yet?
我不斷聽到電話留言…
No. I got her answering machine.
- 派一組人去 - 已經派了
- Send a unit. - I sent a unit.
沒有回音，
There's no answer.
那個經理還沒有回家
The apartment manager's not in.
打電話給她
Call her.
- 剛打了  -再打一次
- I just called her. - Call her again.
給我一支香煙
Give me a cigarette.
你好
Hi, there.
捉弄到你了，你在跟答錄機談話
Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但別害羞，答錄機也需要愛的
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too,
跟它談談吧，金珍，就是我…
so talk to it...
或者莎拉會回覆你的，等候訊號
又是一樣
Same shit.
我現在聽到了
I can hear it now.
就叫他做「電話簿殺手」吧
He's gonna be called the goddamn Phone Book Killer.
我討厭這些報界觸目的案件
I hate these press cases.
特別是變態的觸目案件
Especially the weird press cases.
你去哪裡？
Where are you going?
發表聲明
To make a statement.
叫這班走狗替我們工作
Maybe make these jackals work for us for a change.
若我可以在11點前上電視…
If I can get on the tube by 11:00,
或者她會找我們的
maybe she'll call us.
怎樣？ 我的樣子怎樣？
Well, how do I look?
-很難看，老總  -不錯
- Like shit, boss. - Your mama.
剛收到消息. 警方已經宣佈了...
This just in. Police have announced the name of the victim
第二名死者的姓名
in the second of two execution style murders...
是今天發生的命案
...which took place today.
很奇怪，兩名死者都是同名同姓
Incredibly, the names of the two victims...
...are virtually identical.
兩小時前，35歲的莎拉康納…
Two hours ago, 35-year-old Sarah Ann Connor...
被發現死在寓所裡
...was pronounced dead...
- 轉台吧 - 莎拉康納…
- Can we change this? - Sarah Louise Connor...
別碰它
Don't touch it!
在她家中被殺
警方拒絕猜測…
Police are refusing to speculate on...
兩宗案件的類似之處…
...the similarity between the shooting deaths
現在仍未發現兩者之間有何關連
and no other connection...
...between the two victims has been established yet.
我們會隨時為大家報導最新消息
We'll have more on this late-breaking story as it comes in.
（莎拉康納…）
（黑科技酒吧）
- 有電話嗎？ - 在裡面
- Hey, you got a phone? - It's in the back.
四塊半.
Hey, $4.50.
你已接通洛杉磯警局緊急熱線
You have reached...
...the Los Angeles Police Department emergency number.
我們的線路正在忙線中
All lines are busy.
如果需召警車支援，請稍候
If you need a police car sent out to you, stay on the line.
在第三街與奧林匹克街交界 的鮑勃酒舖附近有狀況
走開
Pugsley! Shoo!
我會拿你來製皮帶
Go on. I'm gonna make a belt out of you.
別逼我打你
Don't make me bust you up, man.
你好
Hi, there.
捉弄到你了，
Fooled you.
你在跟答錄機談話
You're talking to a machine.
但別害羞，答錄機也需要愛的
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too.
跟它談談吧…金珍，就是我…
So talk to it and Ginger, that's me,
或者莎拉會回覆你的，
or Sarah will get back to you.
等候訊號
Walit for the beep.
金珍，是莎拉，快接聽
Ginger, this is Sarah. Pick up if you're there.
我在比科大道的黑科技酒吧
I'm at this place on Pico Boulevard called Tech Noir.
我很害怕
I'm really scared.
有人跟蹤我
I think that there's somebody after me.
我希望你快點聽這個留言
I hope that you play this back soon.
我想你來接我
I need you and Matt to come and pick me up as soon as possible.
警方不停轉接我的電話線
The police keep transferring me around.
我會再試的
I'm gonna give 'em another try.
這裡的號碼是5559175
The number here is 555-9175.
快找我，我要你幫忙
Call me, kiddo. I need your help.
（莎拉康納）
是她
It's her.
- 莎拉康納？我是特斯勒警長 - 聽著…
Sarah Connor? It's Lieutenant Traxler.
別要我等或者轉線
Lieutenant, don't put me on hold...
...and don't transfer me to another department.
我不會，你在哪裡？
Don't worry, I won't. Just relax. Can you tell me where you are?
一間叫黑科技的酒吧
I'm in this bar called Tech Noir.
我知道，在比科大道
Yeah, I know it. It's on Pico.
你沒事吧？
Are you all right?
沒事，
Yeah, but I don't wanna leave.
但我覺得有人在跟蹤我
I think there's a guy following me.
注意聽好，
Now, listen carefully.
你待在公共場合會比較安全
You're in a public place so you'll be safe...
我們會盡快趕來
...till we get there.
留在原地，
But stay visible.
別出去，別上廁所
Don't go outside or even to the restroom.
- 我會很快派一輛車來 - 好的
- I'll have a car there in a minute. - OK.
那個傢伙沒有付錢
Hey, that guy didn't pay.
你想活著就跟我來
Come with me if you wanna live.
快點
Come on!
這是1- L19，有人襲擊後逃跑
This is one-L-19. I got a hit-and-run felony.
可疑車輛是舊型灰色福特...
Suspect vehicle: late model gray Ford...
...在第七街向西逃走
...headed westbound on Seventh.
他開得很快
He's really moving, punching lights all the way.
馬上派救護車來第七街
I'm gonna need an ambulance at Seventh...
和百老匯街交界
...and Broadway right now.
別動
Hold it!
所有單位留意一輛舊型灰色福特
最後被發現在第七街 和百老匯街交界，向西行走
坐穩
Hold on.
你有沒有受傷？
Are you injured?
你有沒有中槍？
Are you shot?
照我的話做
Do exactly what I say.
照著做
Exactly.
不要動
Don't move unless I say.
不要發出聲音
Don't make a sound unless I say.
明白嗎？
Do you understand?
- 明白嗎？ - 明白
- Do you understand? - Yes!
求你別傷害我
Please don't hurt me.
我是來幫你的
I'm here to help you.
我姓瑞斯，科技部隊中士
I'm Reese. Sergeant Tech-Com.
DN38416，受命來保護你
DN38416. Assigned to protect you.
你是被毀滅的目標
You've been targeted for termination.
嫌犯在國家街和奧林匹克街交界 1- L19，請通話
這是1- L19，在奧林匹克街向西行
This is one-L-19. Westbound on Olympic,
接近奧佛蘭道
approaching Overland.
一定是搞錯了
This is a mistake.
我沒做過什麼
I didn't do anything.
不，你會做的
No, but you will.
你保住性命是很重要的事
It's very important that you live.
不是真的 那個人怎能站起來追你…
This isn't true. How could that man just get up after you...
它不是人.  是機器，
It's not a man. A machine.
一個魔鬼終結者. 電腦達因系統101型號.
A Terminator. Cyberdyne Systems model 101.
機器？
A machine?
像機械人？
Like a robot?
不是機械人
Not a robot.
是電子人，電腦控制的生物
A cyborg. Cybernetic organism.
不，他剛才在流血
No. He was bleeding.
等一下
Just a second.
趴下
Get your head down!
好，聽著
All right, listen.
魔鬼終結者是個混合體
The Terminator's an infiltration unit.
半人半機械
Part man, part machine.
內部是一個超合金的戰鬥骨架
Underneath it's a hyper-alloy combat chassis.
由微型處理器操作
Microprocessor controlled.
全副武裝，非常強勁
Fully armored, very tough.
但外表是活人組織
But outside it's living human tissue.
肌肉、皮膚、毛髮、血液
Flesh, skin, hair, blood...
都是為電子人培植的
grown for the cyborgs.
- 你想我怎樣做？ - 留心聽著
- Look, Reese, I don't know... - Pay attention.
我要丟棄這輛車
I gotta ditch this car.
600系列有塑膠皮膚 很容易認得出
The 600-Series had rubber skin. We spotted them easy.
但這批是新造的，它們很像人類
But these are new. They look human.
流汗、口臭，諸如此類 很難辨認
Sweat, bad breath, everything. Very hard to spot.
我要等他向你下手才可以對付他
I had to wait till he moved on you before I could zero him.
聽著…我不是蠢才.
Look, I am not stupid.
他們還不能製造那樣的東西
They cannot make things like that yet.
還不可以
Not yet.
40年後就可以了
Not for about 40 years.
你是說它來自未來？
Are you saying it's from the future?
一個有可能的未來
One possible future.
從你的角度看 我對科技一竅不通
From your point of view, I don't know tech stuff.
那麼你也是來自未來？
Then you're from the future, too. Is that right?
- 對  - 對
- Right. - Right.
電子人感覺不到痛楚
Cyborgs don't feel pain.
我感覺得到. 不要再那樣做.
I do. Don't do that again.
放我走
Just let me go.
聽著… 還有搞清楚點
Listen and understand.
那個終結者就在外面
That Terminator is out there.
它是沒情可講的
It can't be bargained with,
也不講道理
it can't be reasoned with.
它不會感到可惜...
It doesn't feel pity...
...或後悔或者恐懼，
...or remorse or fear
它絕不會罷休
and it absolutely will not stop,
永遠不會, 直到你死掉.
ever, until you are dead.
你可否制止它？
Can you stop it?
我不知道
I don't know.
靠這些武器，我不知道
With these weapons, I don't know.
所有單位，灰色福特…
All units. Ford suspect vehicle...
在一個停車場裡發現可疑車輛
...has been found in a parking structure...
地點是第四街和百老匯街交界
位置是下層
疑匪是個年約25歲，身高六呎 穿綠色外衣的白種男人
最後被發現在…
瑞斯？
Reese,
為何是我？
why me?
它為何要對付我？
Why does it want me?
曾經發生了一場核戰
There was a nuclear war.
未來數年後…
A few years from now...
這裡的一切…
...all this,
這個地方，所有的東西…
this whole place, everything...
...都會消失.  就此消失.
...it's gone. Just gone.
有一些生還者
There were survivors.
零星的… 散落各地.
Here, there.
沒有人知道是誰發動戰爭
Nobody even knew who started it.
是那些機器
It was the machines, Sarah.
我不明白
I don't understand.
防衛網絡電腦
Defense network computers.
新型的, 功能強勁...
New, powerful...
...接駁到所有的東西
...hooked into everything,
被委託操控一切的重任
trusted to run it all.
他們說它變得聰明起來
They say it got smart...
一種智慧的新秩序
a new order of intelligence.
它視所有人類為威脅
Then it saw all people as a threat.
不能與我們共存
Not just the ones on the other side.
它在剎那間決定了我們的命運
It decided our fate in a microsecond.
滅絕
Extermination.
你可有目睹這場戰爭？
Did you see this war?
沒有. 我在戰後長大.
No. I grew up after.
在廢墟中成長
In the ruins.
挨飢抵餓. 躲避那些HK.
Starving. Hiding from the H-Ks.
- HK？ - 追捕殺手
- H-Ks? - Hunter-killers.
機械工廠製造的巡邏機器
Patrol machines built in automated factories.
我們大部分人被圍捕
Most of us were rounded up,
關在營裡等候被逐一消滅
put in camps for orderly disposal.
這是被雷射掃瞄器烙下的
This was burned in by laser scanner.
我們有部分人得以活下來…
Some of us were kept alive.
負責…
To work.
搬運屍體
Loading bodies.
那些消滅單位日以繼夜地運作
The disposal units ran night and day.
我們差點就喪命
We were that close to going out forever.
但有一個人…
But there was one man...
教我們反抗，
...who taught us to fight.
衝擊監禁營的線路
To storm the wire of the camps.
把那些金屬混蛋撞個稀巴爛
To smash those metal motherfuckers into junk.
他扭轉了局勢，帶我們脫離險境
He turned it around. He brought us back from the brink.
他姓康納
His name was Connor.
約翰康納
John Connor.
你的兒子
Your son, Sarah.
你未出生的兒子
Your unborn son.
你來開車
Drive!
瑞斯!
Reese!
不，瑞斯，不
No, Reese. No, no,
不，他們會殺死你的
no. They'll kill you.
在凱迪拉克車裡的人 立刻舉高雙手
You in the Cadillac, let me see your hands now.
下車
Get out of the car.
跪下
Drop to your knees.
下車
Out of the car.
跪下
Drop to the ground.
所有PC- 207單位注意 疑匪已被制伏
取消進一步支援
莎拉…
Sarah. Sarah,
喝一點吧
try to drink some of this.
你肯定是他們？
Listen, are you sure it's them?
我應該看看屍體的
I mean, maybe I should look at the bodies.
已經證實了他們的身分 沒有錯的
No. They've been identified and there's no doubt.
天
金珍
Ginger.
- 小伙子 - 莎拉...
- Kiddo. - Sarah...
這是西伯曼醫生
Sarah, this is Dr. Silberman.
你好，莎拉
Hi, Sarah.
我想你告訴他，
I want you to tell him...
瑞斯對你說的一切
...everything Reese told you.
你應付得來嗎？
Do you feel up to that?
可以吧
Yeah, I guess so.
你是個醫生？
You're a doctor?
犯罪學心理醫生
Criminal psychologist.
瑞斯是不是瘋了？
Is Reese crazy?
我們就是要查證一下
That's what we're gonna find out.
你是個軍人吧
So you're a soldier.
保衛著誰？
Fighting for whom?
隸屬第132團，由貝里率領
With the 132nd under Perry.
由21年到27年
From '21 to '27.
那是…2027年？
That's the year 2027?
對. 後來我被派到…
That's right. Then I was assigned...
- 很好  -...當約翰康納的部下
- This is fucking great. - ...under John Connor.
- 敵人是誰？ - 一個電腦防衛系統…
- Who was the enemy? - A computer defense system built...
該死，對不起
Goddamn. Sorry.
電腦動力系統替薩諾力製造的
...built for SAC-NORAD by Cyberdyne Systems.
是吧
I see.
這個電腦…
And this computer...
...以為殺了敵人的母親就可以勝利
...thinks it can win by killing the mother of its enemy.
把他在孕育前就殺掉
Killing him, in effect, before he's even conceived.
算是倒逆的墮胎？
A sort of retroactive abortion?
西伯曼笑死我了
Silberman cracks me up.
那個傢伙把他弄得一頭霧水
Last week, a guy burned his Afghan.
- 他先弄得一團糟 - 閉嘴
- He screwed it first... - Ed, shut up.
那麼為何它…
Why didn't...
...不殺死約翰康納？
...the computer just kill Connor then?
為何要有這個終結者的計劃？
Why this elaborate scheme with the Terminator?
我沒有選擇
It had no choice.
它們的防禦網絡被摧毀
Their defense grid was smashed.
我們贏了
We'd won.
殺掉約翰康納也不會有何分別
Taking out Connor then would make no difference.
天網要剷除他整個組織
Skynet had to wipe out his entire existence.
是不是當你們操控了實驗室時 找到的…
Is that when you captured the lab complex and found...
...那個什麼？
...What is it called?
時空轉移裝置？
The time displacement equipment?
不錯
That's right.
那個終結者已經穿越過來了
The Terminator had already gone through.
康納派我來攔截
Connor sent me to intercept
它們把整個地方炸毀了
and they blew the whole place.
你怎麼回去？
Well, how are you supposed to get back?
我不可以
I can't.
沒有人可以回去
Nobody goes home.
沒有別人可以過來
Nobody else comes through.
只有他…和我
It's just him and me.
只有他… 和我
為何你沒有帶武器？
Why didn't you bring any weapons?
一些更先進的武器？
Something more advanced.
你們沒有鐳射槍的嗎？
Don't you have ray guns?
鐳射槍.
Ray guns.
給我看看一件未來的科技
Show me a piece of future technology.
你要光著身體
You go naked.
它跟由生物產生的磁場有關
Something about the field generated by a living organism.
- 死物是不行的 - 為什麼？
- Nothing dead will go. - Why?
那鬼東西不是我製造的
I didn't build the fucking thing.
好的… 但這個電子人，若它是金屬的…
OK, OK. But this cyborg, if it's metal...?
被活組織包著的
Surrounded by living tissue.
對，是的
Oh, right.
這可真有看頭 我可以因他功成名就
This is great stuff. I could make a career out of this guy.
看這個多聰明？不需要證據
See how clever it is? It doesn't require a shred of proof.
大部分神經病幻覺都很複雜
Most paranoid delusions are intricate,
但這個卻很精明
but this is brilliant.
為何另外那兩個女人會被殺？
Why were the other two women killed?
大部分記錄都在戰爭中遺失了
Most records were lost in the war.
天網對康納的母親幾乎一無所知
Skynet knew almost nothing about Connor's mother.
她的全名… 她住在哪裡
Her full name, where she lived.
他們只知道在哪個城市
They just knew the city.
那個終結者只是受系統操控
The Terminator was just being systematic.
我們再談談…
Let's go back...
你聽夠了
Look, you have heard enough.
我已經回答了你的問題
I have answered your questions,
現在我要見莎拉
now I have to see Sarah Connor.
我可不能作主
I'm afraid that's not up to me.
- 那為何我要跟你談？ - 因為…
Then why am I talking to you?
- 誰是主管？ - 求你…
- Who is in authority here? - Please...
閉嘴
Shut up!
你還是不明白，對不對？
You still don't get it, do you?
他會找到她的
He'll find her.
他就是要那樣做
That's what he does.
他只會那樣做
That's all he does.
你制止不了他的
You can't stop him.
他會宰了你，捏住她的喉嚨
He'll reach down her throat
挖出她的心臟
and pull her fucking heart out!
- 醫生  - 放開我!
- Doc. - Let go of me!
對不起
Sorry.
瑞斯是瘋了？
So Reese is crazy?
用技術性的用語…
In technical terminology,
他是個瘋子
he's a loon.
莎拉，這是他們所謂的盔甲
Sarah, this is what they call body armor.
我們的特種部隊都穿著這個
Our TAC guys wear these.
能擋12口徑的火力
It'll stop a 12-gauge round.
那個人一定是穿了它
This other individual must've been wearing one under his coat.
觸摸一下吧
Feel that. Go ahead.
打碎擋風玻璃又怎樣解釋？
He punched through the windshield.
他可能服食了麻醉藥
He was probably on PCP.
若他折斷了手
Broke every bone in his hand.
幾小時也感覺不到的
He wouldn't feel it for hours.
這個傢伙…看見嗎？
There was this guy once... You see this scar?
- 拿著. - 謝謝.
- Here. - Thank you.
這裡有一張沙發
There's a couch in this other room.
躺下來睡一會吧
Stretch out and get some sleep.
你媽要一小時後才從大熊鎮抵達
Be at least an hour...
...before your mother gets here from Big Bear.
我睡不著
I can't sleep.
試試吧
Try.
那張沙發其貌不揚，但很舒服的
It may not look it, but that couch is very comfortable.
你會絕對安全的
You'll be perfectly safe.
這座大廈裡有30個警員
We got 30 cops in this building.
謝謝你
Thank you.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
我是莎拉康納的朋友
I'm a friend of Sarah Connor.
我知道她在這裡
I was told she's here.
我可否見她？
Could I see her?
不可以，她在錄口供
No. Can't see her. She's making a statement.
她在哪裡？
Where is she?
要一會兒的 你想等的話，
It may take a while. If you wanna wait,
那邊有張長椅
there's a bench over there.
我會回來
I'll be back.
怎麼回事？
有槍聲
- 是不是恐怖分子？ - 快走
- Are they terrorists? - Let's go, let's go!
別走開
Stay here.
- 我們快離開這裡 - 來吧
Let's get outta here!
快點…
我看到他
看著他
Watch him.
- 自動式武器 - 快點，走吧
著火了…
艾特
Ed...
Hey!
莎拉
Sarah!
瑞斯
Reese.
這邊
This way.
新聞時間，4點36分
KFLB news time 4:36.
（燃料）
主要新聞 加州歷來最大型的…
Top story of the hour: the largest...
...single law enforcement mobilization
...執法行動正在展開
in California history is currently underway.
五個南部縣區正在大舉搜捕…
Police in five counties are engaged in a massive manhunt for...
拿著
Take this.
我們把這個推離公路
All right, let's get this off the road.
你冷嗎？
You cold?
凍僵了
Freezing.
瑞斯…
Reese?
- 你有名字嗎？  - 凱爾
- You got a first name? - Kyle.
凱爾, 你穿越時空時是怎樣的？
Kyle, what's it like when you go through time?
白光
White light.
痛楚
Pain.
或許就像出生時一樣吧
It's like being born maybe.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我剛才吃了一記
I caught one back there.
你中槍了？
You mean you got shot?
不是很嚴重
It's not bad.
- 我們要找醫生 - 沒事的，算了吧
- We gotta get you to a doctor. - It's OK. Forget it.
算了？你瘋了嗎？
What do you mean, forget it? Are you crazy?
脫下它
Take this off.
天啊
Jesus.
它穿過了皮肉
See? It passed right through the meat.
這會使我作嘔
This is gonna make me puke.
- 你可以跟我說嗎？ - 說什麼？
- Would you just talk about something? - What?
不知道，隨便說吧
I don't know. Anything. Just talk.
談談我的兒子
Tell me about my son.
他有我這麼高大
He's about my height.
他有你的眼睛
He has your eyes.
他是怎樣的？
What's he like?
你信任他
You trust him.
他有一種力量
He's got a strength.
我願意為約翰康納犧牲
I'd die for John Connor.
我現在至少知道給他取什麼名字
Well, at least now I know what to name him.
你不知道他父親是誰吧
Don't suppose you know who the father is...
好讓我遇上他時不會叫他滾開
...so I won't tell him to get lost?
約翰從來沒有提起他
John never said much about him.
- 我知道他在戰前死了 - 等一會
- I know he dies before the war... - Wait.
我不想知道
I don't wanna know.
是不是約翰派你來的？
So was it John that sent you here?
是我自願的
I volunteered.
為什麼？
Why?
有機會認識傳奇人物
It was a chance to meet the legend.
莎拉康納
Sarah Connor,
她教她的兒子抵抗…組織,
who taught her son to fight, organize,
準備，從他小時就開始教導他
prepare from when he was a kid.
當其他人還在戰前躲避時
When you were in hiding before the war.
你用過去式說一些
You're talking about things...
我還沒有做的事
...I haven't done yet in the past tense.
真的令我發瘋
It's driving me crazy.
你肯定找對了人？
Are you sure you have the right person?
肯定
I'm sure.
不是吧，我像未來的母親？
Come on. Do I look like the mother of the future?
我堅強嗎？
I mean, am I tough?
有組織能力？ 我連讓自己收支平衡都不會
Organized? I can't even balance my checkbook.
我沒有要求這個榮譽 也不想要它
Look, Reese, I didn't ask for this honor and I don't want it.
絕對不要
Any of it.
你兒子要我告訴你
Your son gave me a message to give to you.
他要我背熟它
Made me memorize it.
「感謝你在黑暗年代的勇氣」
"Thank you, Sarah, for your courage through the dark years.
「你要面對的事我幫不到你...
I can't help you with what you must soon face,
...只能說未來還未定案」
except to say the future is not set.
「你一定要比你想像中更堅強」
You must be stronger than you imagine you can be.
「你一定要活下去 否則我永遠不會存在」
You must survive or I will never exist."
就是這樣
That's all.
包紮得很好
It's a good field dressing.
你喜歡嗎？
You like it?
這是我的第一次
It's my first.
睡一會吧，快天亮了
Get some sleep. It'll be light soon.
好的
OK.
再跟我談一會
Talk to me some more.
談什麼？
About what?
告訴我你從哪裡來
Tell me about where you're from.
好的
All right.
你白天躲藏起來
You stay down by day,
但在晚上你可以到處活動
but at night you can move around.
你仍然要小心 因為追捕殺手會用紅外線
You still have to be careful because the H-Ks use infrared.
但它們不是太聰明
But they're not too bright.
約翰教我們對付它們的方法
John taught us ways to dust them.
就是當那些滲透者出現的時候
That's when the infiltrators started to appear.
終結者是最新型的…
The Terminators were the newest.
最難對付的
The worst.
它正在以搜尋模式闖進你的防區
Traversing your sector in search mode.
在你以北750米的位置
750 meters north of your position.
我們走吧
Let's go.
瑞斯，DN- 384…
Reese. DN384...
對，讓他進來
Right. Let himin.
我們的監察者有一隻爪壞了 所以要減少巡邏
收到，揚基17，你可以安全折返
終結者…
Terminator!
我夢見一些狗
I was dreaming about dogs.
我們用牠們來提防終結者
We use 'em to spot Terminators.
你的世界很可怕
Your world is pretty terrifying.
老友，你裡面有隻死貓嗎？
Hey, buddy, you got a dead cat in there or what?
（可能的回應：是、不是或走開）
（去你的，混蛋）
去你的，混蛋
Fuck you, asshole.
（媽媽的小屋 大熊鎮雲杉路181號）
該死
God damn.
謝謝
Thank you.
（迪基旅館）
這個夠不夠？
Is this enough?
夠了，我不想問你從哪裡得來的
Yeah, it's enough. I don't wanna ask where you got it.
- 來了 - 我們要一個房間
- I'm coming. - We need a room.
- 好的 - 要有廚房
- All right. - With a kitchen.
有廚房的嗎？
Do you have one with a kitchen?
我很想洗澡
I am dying for a shower.
還要檢查你的繃帶
We should check your bandage, too.
稍後吧，我要出去買東西
Later. I'm going out for supplies.
拿著這個
Keep this.
媽，我不能告訴你我在哪裡
No, I can't tell you where I am, Mom.
有人叫我不要說出來
I was told not to say.
我要知道在哪裡可以找到你
But I need to know where to reach you.
你叫我像個逃犯般躲在小屋裡
You tell me to hide out at the cabin
但你卻不願告訴我發生什麼事？
and you won't tell me what's going on?
我很擔心
I am worried sick here.
好吧. 這是電話號碼.
OK. OK, here's the number.
- 準備好了嗎？ - 準備好了，說吧
- You ready? - Yes. Go ahead.
是408-555…1439
It's 408-555-1439.
九號房，
Room nine.
- 記下了嗎？ - 記下了.
- Got it? - I've got it.
我要掛了
I gotta go.
抱歉我現在不能多說
I'm sorry I can't tell you more right now.
媽，我愛你
I love you, Mom.
我也愛你
I love you, too, sweetheart.
- 迪基旅館 - 把你們的地址給我
- Tiki Motel. - Give me your address there.
買了什麼？
What have we got?
樟腦丸…
Mothballs...
玉米糖漿
corn syrup...
阿摩尼亞
ammonia.
晚餐吃什麼？
What's for dinner?
- 塑料炸彈 - 好極了
- Plastique. - That sounds good.
這是什麼？
What is it?
硝酸甘油固定劑
It's a nitroglycerin base.
這樣會固定一點
It's a bit more stable.
我小時候學會的
I learned to make it when I was a kid.
不要沾到引線上
Make sure there's none on the threads.
這樣
Like this.
把蓋扭上
Screw the end cap on.
輕輕的
Very gently.
你的童年一定很好玩
You must've had a fun childhood.
很好
That's good.
再多做六個，我會開始做信管
All right. Six more like that and I'll get started on the fuses.
他會找到我們，是不是？
He'll find us, won't he?
可能吧
Probably.
這件事永遠不會完結，對嗎？
It'll never be over, will it?
看看我，我在顫抖
Look at me. I'm shaking.
好一個傳奇人物
Some legend.
你一定很失望了
You must be pretty disappointed.
不是.  我沒有失望.
No, I'm not.
凱爾,  你那個時代的女人…
Kyle, the women in your time,
她們是怎樣的？
what are they like?
是精銳的戰士
Good fighters.
我不是那個意思
That's not what I meant.
有沒有意中人？
Was there someone special?
意中人？
Someone...?
女孩子
A girl, you know.
沒有
No.
從來沒有
Never.
從來沒有？
Never?
我很難過
I'm sorry.
我真的很難過
I'm so sorry.
這麼多痛苦
So much pain.
痛苦是可以抑制的
Pain can be controlled.
只要你不去想它
You just disconnect it.
那麼你沒有感覺？
So you feel nothing?
約翰康納曾經把你一張照片給我
John Connor gave me a picture of you once.
當時我不明白原因
I didn't know why at the time.
它很舊了
It was very old,
有點破爛, 也褪色了.
torn, faded.
你當時很年輕，像現在一樣
You were young like you are now.
你看來…  有點悲傷.
You seemed just a little sad.
我時常猜想你當時在想著什麼
I used to always wonder what you were thinking at that moment.
我謹記著每一條線…
I memorized every line...
每一條曲線
...every curve.
莎拉，我穿越了時空來找你
I came across time for you, Sarah.
我愛你.  我一直愛著你.
I love you. I always have.
我不該那樣說的
I shouldn't have said that.
想快點
Think fast.
交換位置
Trade places.
快點!  開快點!
Faster! Drive faster!
凱爾!  我的天.
Kyle! Oh, my God.
凱爾.
Kyle.
混蛋
Son-of-a-bitch!
你別走開
You stay here.
我們快離開…
Let's get outta here.
下車
Get out.
凱爾，站起來
Kyle. Come on. Get up.
幫我
來吧
Kyle, come on.
幫我!  快走…
Help me! Get out. Get out.
走
快點
不要停，走
Don't stop. Run!
莎拉？
Sarah!
凱爾
Kyle.
凱爾. 凱爾..
Kyle. Kyle...
凱爾，我們成功了
We did it, Kyle.
我們成功了
We got him.
不
No!
等一會
Wait.
你幹什麼？
What are you doing?
掩護，讓它追蹤不到我們
Cover, so he can't track us.
（啟動自動化生產序列）
快點! 來吧.
Come on! Come on.
不，凱爾
No, Kyle!
來吧
Come on!
- 來吧 - 別理會我
- Come on! - Leave me here.
快走，瑞斯
Move it, Reese!
站起來，士兵
On your feet, soldier!
站起來
On your feet!
快走
Move it!
後面，去後面
Get back. Go back.
- 莎拉，快逃 - 不
- Run, Sarah. - No.
快跑
Run!
來吧，混蛋
Come on, motherfucker.
不…
No.
（啟動卸貨）
混蛋，你被毀滅了
You're terminated, fucker.
凱爾
Kyle.
11月10日，第7卷
Tape seven. November 10.
我說到哪裡？
Where was I?
最難決定的是該告訴你什麼
What's most difficult is trying to decide...
...what to tell you and what not to.
但到你長大明白時
But I guess I have a while...
我還有時間考慮
...before you're old enough to understand these tapes.
現在這是我的問題
They're more for me at this point...
讓我想個清楚
...just so that I can get it straight.
加滿它
Fill her up.
我是否該告訴你 關於你父親的事？
Should I tell you about your father?
那是個難題
Boy, that's a tough one.
你知道他是你的父親
Will it affect your decision to send him here,
可會影響你派他來這裡的決定？
knowing that he is your father?
如果你不派凱爾來，就不會有你
If you don't send Kyle, you can never be.
天，想著這件事會使人發瘋的
God, a person could go crazy thinking about this.
我相信我會告訴你的
I suppose I will tell you.
這是我至少該做的
I owe him that.
如果你知道這個…
Maybe it'll help if...
也許有幫助的
...you know that in the few hours that we had together...
在我們共處的時光裡…
我們愛了一生一世
...we loved a lifetime's worth.
他說什麼？
What did he just say?
他說：「小姐，你很漂亮」
He says you're very beautiful.
他不敢問你拿五元的照相費
He is ashamed to ask you...
...for five American dollars for this picture.
但如果他不問你 他父親就會打他
But if he doesn't, his father will beat him.
孩子，真會做生意
Pretty good hustle, kid.
他說什麼？
What did he just say?
他說風暴快來了
He said there's a storm coming in.
我知道
I know.
（鳴謝哈倫艾里森）
English - US